[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
so as you all know I have published
around
nine YouTube videos on tricentistoska
latest version 16.
so in this session this is our lesson 10
in this session I'm gonna cover how can
we populate desktop values of your test
cases so if you remember in my previous
two sessions
I have started
creating tutorials on test case
automation
so in test case automation
that means to automate your test cases
by using price and testoster there are
sequence of steps that we need to follow
so in my previous two sessions I have
explained you step one where we created
test case folder structure and also I've
explained you
step two where we have created steps for
your test case folder structure
so in this session lesson 10 I'm gonna
teach you how to populate the step
values for your test cases
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay so as I explained you we already
created test steps now we need to
populate desktop values so how to
populate desktop values in latest
version Tasker 16 I'm gonna teach you so
populate your test steps with values in
order to instruct Tasker to see here the
system under test accordingly
and then we are going to use some basic
values to populate the steps and the
basic data types I'm not going to cover
all the data types in this session
only Limited Basic data type I'm going
to cover
and then
tester values can be seen entered or
modified from test case section of your
tricent testoster that I'm gonna show
you and also I'm going to teach you how
can to view them to view the test step
values you just need to expand the test
steps so that you can see the test step
values
so they expand all option can be used on
test tips level
alt or desktop folder level or test case
level
okay so now let's jump onto the system
and see how can we populate desktop
values
so that our test case automation is
almost complete
okay so this is my task of 16 okay so in
my previous session session nine
we have entered or we have created test
steps
for your test case structure under
precondition we added almost like three
steps
under process
for all the subfolders we added all our
test steps by using modules okay it's
very important for you guys to visit my
previous session
to continue with this particular
session okay lesson 10. so now so let's
populate the values as I explained you
in the slide okay
first so let's go one by one okay
in
precondition
first we will be opening the URL correct
so this is this is the test step that we
added
opening the URL if you see under open
URL module you have URL correct so here
you need to enter the URL and see the
demo webshop URL
okay copy this demo webshop URL
and paste
here
okay so this is my demo webshop URL
correct
and as soon as you paste the URL your
action mode will be turning to input
so in this session most of the times we
are going to use the action Mode called
input and rest of the action modes I am
going to cover in the next session okay
and also you will have a data type so
I'm not going to see the date different
you have a different data types called
Date numeric string all these things so
for this session
will stick to the string data type okay
so this is my string data type
I am entering the URL once you enter the
URL so let's go to URL you will be
clicking on login correct so that is
where we have here okay this is my top
menu under top menu I captured all these
controls
so this is my login control correct so
to click on login
so there are two methods either you can
just enter
cross
as soon as you enter cross the input
action mode input will be populated
automatically
this clicks what happens Tasker will
steer your system under an application
it is going to click on login link
or you can leave this blank also
and then this input will click on this
but it is recommended to enter some
values so that it is easy for you to
recognize that
you are performing some action for this
particular link I mean for this
particular control okay it is
recommended okay that is one thing and
once you click on login you are gonna
enter the credentials correct so that is
my next step
you're gonna enter your email address so
this is my email edit box control
enter your email
and then you need to enter your password
okay
as soon as you enter the password this
input if you see all the action modes
are converting to input okay
and then
you'll be clicking on login
so again here this is your button you
just need to enter X so that it clicks
on login button that's it
so our precondition
entering the values to your precondition
steps are done
and now go to process
for the process so once you let me log
in so that it is easy for you to
understand okay
okay let me copy this email address I
think we entered the wrong email ID let
me see
let's go back to email ID and correct
our email ID okay
email address let me correct my email
address
okay done so now
so once you click here
what we are going to do you need to
navigate to operation shoe from the
category so here from product categories
select apples and choose
done so once you navigate to apprent
shoes apparel shoes here you need to
select your blue jeans
right
once you select the blue jeans for this
year navigate to Blue Jeans
so this is my link just I'm gonna enter
X
that will click on that link
and then
you need to provide your quantity and
click on add to Carter
right Order Blue Jeans provide the
quantity let's say 10.
and click on add to cart button
enter X
done so I'm populating the test step
values okay it is very important these
values will steer your application
accordingly okay
so let's entertain
click on add to cut
and as part of start
checkout process you need to click on
shopping cart this is my shopping cart
right so that's why I'm going to enter X
here
done
so let's do the same thing here click on
shopping cart
once you go to shopping cart here you
need to agree to the terms
and then check out click on checkout
so that's what I'm gonna do
here terms of your service is true you
need to check the check box so that's
why you need to select true
and then click on
checkout button
correct so that is done and then your
checkout process begins
what you need to enter billing address
and just you need to click on continue
because the billing address is already
configured click on continue so that
means here billing address
X that's gonna click on continue button
and then you need to select in-store
pickup here let me
oh no sorry I think I just need to click
on continue so I don't want to do in
install pickup just I can continue click
on continue so let me
enter click on continue that means X
so once you click on continue
the shipping method I need to select
ground
so for that shipping method here if you
see ground shipping method and then
click on continue so that means again
against continue
control just enter X
and then your payment method comes into
picture
the payment method is
credit card payment method correct
credit card I want to select credit card
right so for that payment method select
credit card
and then
click on continue
enter X
so then
you will be providing your payment
information
sorry credit card information
select Visa so that means your Select
Credit Card my credit card type is Visa
and credit card holder name so I have
all my credit card details here copy
and then what is your credit card number
this is my credit card number
and then what is your expiration date
0 4
and then your code
is one two three card code is one two
three and then you will be clicking on
continue it's correct
let me
copy
let me do this here as well your credit
card number
enter
and then
0 4 2021 0 4 2021
oh let's let's keep 2023. and one two
three click on continue
so
so let's enter 2023 here okay
okay so you'll be clicking on continue
okay once you click on continue you need
to verify the prices all the prices are
correct or not so that we are not gonna
do in this session okay
after that I need to confirm the order
so that means
here
you will be clicking on confirm button
correct so just
X against the control confirm button
and then verify success I'm not gonna do
verification of the success here okay
for this session
we are just we are not doing any
verification part so that we are going
to do in the next session and then you
are going to click on continue so here
under post
condition under post condition
see
click on
continue button once you click on
continue button you're gonna log out
correct and then
so that means I need to
enter X
opposite to logout
and then you are going to close the
browser
what is the browser title it's demo I
can put as a demo
star
right this is my browser title
and then
this is my I can select
okay I can just keep on select put as a
select okay
because this is not my input actually
it's just closing the browser
the title of demo star
so that is done so now if you see we
already populated all the values
so if you want to filter all the values
that have I mean sorry if you want to
filter all the steps that has only
values you just need to click on F9
okay so if you click on F9 it shows you
the steps that has a value see simple
showing you again if you click on F9 it
again shows all the steps
okay all the controls that does not have
values and that does have values
let me put as F9
see
done
so that means now we entered all the
values so now
we'll see we can execute this particular
test case and see how it works okay
so I'm not gonna
uh okay so for this session just we will
execute okay it might throw errors it
might not throw errors okay we are not
gonna debug anything we'll make sure
that whatever the values we entered
it works okay but before you run
actually you need to configure
uh you need to configure
your browser okay but however so I'm
gonna teach you how to run your test
case
and how to configure your browsers
in my next session okay so we have
completed automating everything so we
completed automating this end-to-end
scenario by this session but in the next
session I'm gonna run this test case
automated test case
by using some test configurations okay
hope you all understand the concept if
you have any queries please provide your
comments in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank you
hope you all understand the concept of
our step three of your test case
automation where we populate test step
values for your test cases
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
thank you